civilrights.org 2019-07-17

# Privacy Policy - The Leadership Conference on Civil and Human Rights

### 1\. Policy

The Leadership Conference on Civil and Human Rights, Inc. (“The Leadership Conference”) has a long history of working to uphold principles of fairness, justice, and equality under the law for all Americans and working toward the goal of a more open and just society – an America as good as its ideals. Privacy is a cherished American value. In that spirit, The Leadership Conference is committed to respecting the privacy of the users of its website [www.civilrights.org](https://civilrights.org/) (the “Site”). As an advocacy organization, The Leadership Conference’s mission includes providing timely information and using online technologies to communicate with potential advocates and information seekers.

The Leadership Conference includes as part of its mission the effort to build users’ trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting fair information practices. To fulfill this mission, The Leadership Conference agrees to exercise reasonable precautions to maintain the confidentiality of Personal Information (as defined below) provided by you in connection with accessing and using the Site.

This Privacy Policy is part of the Terms and Conditions of the Site, which are binding on all Site users.

As a non-profit, non-partisan advocacy organization providing information and opportunities to contact elected officials, we gather certain types of personally identifiable information from users of the Site, such as your name, e-mail address, street address or other postal mailing address including ZIP code, and telephone number(s) (collectively, “Personal Information”). It is important for you to know how we collect, use, disclose, manage, and store the Personal Information that you may voluntarily provide us as well as the Personal Information that is collected passively through the use of cookies on the Site.

This Privacy Policy sets forth The Leadership Conference’s current policies and practices with respect to Personal Information of the users of the Site. Your continued participation on this Site indicates your acceptance of this Privacy Policy and of the collection, use, disclosure, management, and storage of your Personal Information as described below.

**If you have any objections to this Privacy Policy,**

**you should immediately discontinue use of this Site.**

### 2\. Collection and Use of Personal Information

You may browse the Site without providing any Personal Information. We do not collect Personal Information about you except when you specifically and knowingly provide it. In collecting Personal Information, we limit our use to the reasons given in this Privacy Policy for collection of the Personal Information. The Site provides certain activities where we gather Personal Information from users of the Site, such as an activity that requires that a user complete a registration process. Registration to participate in these Site activities may require the submission of your full name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number(s) and other Personal Information. You will also have the ability to opt-in to additional mailing list services, such as e-mail news alerts.

Unless otherwise provided in a separate registration page, we do not request contact information for a mobile phone, text messaging, or any wireless device that includes a domain name address (such as “wireless.bellsouth.com”) as part of the contact information. Federal law prohibits the sending of commercial e-mail messages directly to a wireless device that uses a domain name, unless you have first given your affirmative consent. We may inadvertently collect a wireless device number that includes a domain name or other information from an e-mail signature block when you send us an inquiry or register for the mailing list. However, we will not knowingly use that contact information for sending commercial e-mail.

We use your Personal Information to provide you with the services you request and to respond to questions related to The Leadership Conference or the Site. We may also use your Personal Information to notify you about updates, action alerts, new features, and activities on behalf of The Leadership Conference or the Site that may be of interest to you. If you do not want to receive such communications from The Leadership Conference, you may opt out of communications, as described below.

From time to time, we may post information about job opportunities on the Site. If you are interested in learning more about these opportunities, you can submit a resume and a cover letter. Applications will be handled by our human resources director and we will make reasonable efforts to review the applications in a timely fashion. We will share your application with members of The Leadership Conference staff to assess your qualifications. We will not distribute or share Personal Information submitted in relation to employment with any third party without your consent.

We may also use your Personal Information for operational and business purposes or to find out how we can improve our organization and Site via surveys or online tracking mechanisms. We aggregate Personal Information collected directly during the registration process and via “cookies” to help us evaluate and modify existing services and features. (For more information on cookies and our related policy see section 8 below). We also use your Personal Information to develop new services and features that may be of interest to you.

### 3\. Disclosure of Information

We will not sell, rent, lease, or otherwise disclose your Personal Information to any third party without your consent. However, The Leadership Conference may disclose Personal Information in special cases: (1) when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) the rights of The Leadership Conference or to anyone that could be harmed by such activities, including threats to the physical safety of any person; (2) when we believe in good faith that the law requires it; (3) to any affiliate of The Leadership Conference including The Leadership Conference Education Fund; and (4) to any third party who may acquire The Leadership Conference.

### 4\. Your Rights to Review and Correct Your Personal Information

You may contact The Leadership Conference by sending an e-mail including the subject line of “Personal Information Request” to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#234a4d454c63404a554a4f514a444b57500d4c5144) to ask if we are keeping Personal Information about you. If we do have Personal Information about you, we will provide you with a readable copy of such Personal Information at no charge. Factual errors in your Personal Information, including out-of-date information, can be corrected by sending a request to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#8fe6e1e9e0cfece6f9e6e3fde6e8e7fbfca1e0fde8) that credibly shows our error.

### 5\. Vendors

We use third-party vendors for various purposes. For example, we use a third-party vendor, [Blue State Digital](https://www.bluestatedigital.com/) (“Blue State Digital”), to store email addresses. When you sign up to receive information from The Leadership Conference or fill out a form to take action, the information is received and stored on Blue State Digital’s servers. The Leadership Conference does not permanently store on its servers e-mail addresses or other Personal Information collected from our Site.

Any time a vendor’s data collection, use or security practices differs from the data collection and/or use practices described in this Privacy Policy in a manner that would impact users of the Site, we will either (1) describe on the page of the Site where such optional functions appear the specific data collection, use, or security practices of such vendor that would apply if you elect to use that optional function, or (2) we will provide a link to that third-party vendor’s privacy policy.

### 6\. Opt-Out Procedures

You may always opt-out of receiving communications from us by clicking on the removal link provided at the bottom of every e-mail sent by The Leadership Conference to change your e-mail preferences.

### 7\. Security of Information

The importance of security for all Personal Information associated with our visitors is of utmost concern to The Leadership Conference. The Personal Information collected through the Site is maintained in a responsible manner consistent with current industry standards.

In order to most efficiently serve you, credit card transactions are handled by established third-party banking, processing agents, and distribution institutions. They receive the information needed to verify and authorize your credit card or other payment information. Financial transactions related to your generous donations to The Leadership Conference including without limitation in connection with awards dinners and advertising are handled by Blue State Digital. Information relating to your financial transactions will not be maintained on The Leadership Conference servers. Please visit [Blue State Digital](https://www.bluestatedigital.com/) to familiarize yourself with its terms and conditions and with its privacy policies.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100 percent secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Personal Information, you acknowledge that: (a) there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control; (b) the security, integrity, and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through the Site cannot be guaranteed; (c) any such information and data may be viewed or tampered with in transit by a third party; and (d) when you transfer any information to us, you do so at your own risk.

### 8\. Cookies

You should be aware that non-Personal Information and data may be automatically collected on the Site through the use of “cookies.” “Cookies” are small text files stored as text on a computer hard drive. Websites can use cookies to recognize repeat visitors, facilitate the visitor’s ongoing access to and use of the site, and allow a site to track usage behavior and compile aggregate data that will allow content improvements. Cookies are not programs that come onto a visitor’s system and damage files. The use of cookies is common in the Internet industry, and most websites use them to provide useful features to their visitors. Generally cookies work by assigning a unique number to the visitor that has no meaning outside the assigning site. If a visitor does not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows the visitor to reject the cookie feature. The Leadership Conference uses cookie technology but only to obtain non-Personal Information from online visitors in order to improve their online experience and facilitate their visit within the Site.

### 9\. Links to Third-Party Websites

The Site may contain links to the websites of third parties not affiliated with The Leadership Conference. You understand, acknowledge, and agree that these links are provided solely as a convenience to you and not as an endorsement by the Site or The Leadership Conference of the content, advertising, or business practices of the third parties. The Leadership Conference is NOT responsible for the privacy practices or the content on any other websites, including any websites that may indicate a special relationship or “partnership” with The Leadership Conference. The Leadership Conference does not disclose unique identifiers to those responsible for the linked websites. The linked websites, however, may collect Personal Information from you when you link to their websites. This collecting of information is not subject to the control of The Leadership Conference. To ensure protection of your privacy, always review the privacy policies of the websites you visit by linking from the Site.

### 10\. Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. We never collect or maintain information at the Site from persons we know to be under age 13, and no part of our Site is designed to attract anyone under age 13. Please do not communicate with or contact us if you are under age 13. By your participation in our Site activities, you certify that you are at least 13 years of age and meet any other eligibility requirements of the Site.

### 11\. Accountability

The Leadership Conference is committed to maintaining and strengthening consumer trust in our Site, by strictly adhering to this Privacy Policy. Further, The Leadership Conference holds its employees responsible to handle personal data consistently with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### 12\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

The Leadership Conference may revise this Privacy Policy over time as new features are added to the Site or as Internet law and standards evolve. We will post those changes prominently but we do recommend that you read this Privacy Policy each time you visit the Site. Changes will not apply retroactively to Personal Information that was collected before the changes to the Privacy Policy, except as may be required by law.

**Last Updated: August 2, 2018**
